<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Answers to the objections against a general insurance.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B17173</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99886814</idno>
  <idno type="VID">189477</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2248537526</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing A3469</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 1888.c.11[51]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R226631</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99886814</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99886814e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B17173)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 189477)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C16:2[55])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Answers to the objections against a general insurance.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1699 or 1700]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>With a docket title.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Insurance --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="answer">
            <pb facs="tcp:189477:1"/>
            <head>Answers to the Objections AGAINST A General INSURANCE.</head>
            <p>
               <label>Objection 1.</label> THAT the Sum proposed is not likely to be raised, because there are not so many Houses, as to Number and Value, as in presum'd.</p>
            <p>
               <label>Answer.</label> That it's impossible to be exactly certain, but the Proposers have taken the best Care they could to be truly and rightly inform'd, and have carefully perus'd the best publick Accompts and Writers, especially Sir <hi>William Pettet,</hi> whose Calculati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on will fully answer this Proposal; and we hope it can't be deny'd, but that the Proposal is very easy, and can't fail to raise a very great Sum.</p>
            <p>
               <label>Objection 2.</label> That take it for granted, as to the Number and Value of the Houses, that it be true; yet there are so many already In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sured, by private Insurances, as amounts to one fifth part of the Houses within the Bills of Mortality; and so, by conse<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quence, will very much lessen the Sum proposed.</p>
            <p>
               <label>Answer.</label> That by an exact Computation of Houses, and taking the several Numbers of Houses from the four <hi>Insurance Offices,</hi> not one fifth part of the Houses within the Bills of Mortality are Insured, and not one House in the whole Nation besides; so that this Objection can but lessen the Sum one fiftieth part, provided all the Houses already Insured be left out. But, with humble Submission, the Parliament is not concerned to take notice of private Agreements, where it stands in Computation with the publick Good. Let them wear out their Pollicies, which are generally but for a little time, and it will be no Injury to those that have Insured by private Pollicies, to Insure again with the publick; for that, in case of Fire, they have two Hands to go to, and receive a double Recompence, and enhance the Value of their Houses: And besides, Houses Insured were never excused upon that account in any Tax whatsoever.</p>
            <p>
               <label>Objection 3.</label> That if the Insurance be above the Value of their Houses, some People may burn their Houses, to make an Advantage of it.</p>
            <p>
               <label>Answer.</label> That the Goods in Houses are generally of greater Value than the Advantage can be gain'd by Burning their Houses; and if the Goods are removed before hand, it will be an Argument of the Party's Design; besides, it's presum'd, that no Person will set his House on Fire, it being Felony.</p>
            <p>
               <label>Objection 4.</label> That if compulsatory unreasonable, if voluntary, it will raise nothing.</p>
            <p>
               <label>Answer.</label> If advantageous reasonably compulsatory, for since the People must pay so much upon some Tax or other, it's not unrea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sonable to compel them to pay upon such account, as is most easy and advantageous to the Payer, as this certainly seems to be, he receiving a Recompence for what he pays.</p>
            <p>As to the voluntary, the very Nature of the People is such, that, as Children, they will neither go to School or take Phy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sick, tho' the greatest Good or Evil depend upon it, unless compell'd. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Thousand <gap reason="illegible" resp="#oxf" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> have attested their Approbation of the Rationality of this Proposal, by their own Acts and Subscriptions, to private Insurances.</p>
            <p>
               <label>Objection 5.</label> That it seems to be very hard upon Houses, which in the Land Tax pay at least equally with Land, should now pay Two Shillings in the Pound more, immediate Payment.</p>
            <p>
               <label>Answer.</label> That it does indeed ease the Land; yet not prejudice the Houses, is manifest, for that, as a yearly Estate, they pay equal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly with Land; yet in this Case they pay in a distinct Capacity, and have an immediate Consideration, being advanced to a proportionable Value and Recompence <hi>in futuro,</hi> in case of Fire. That seeming Hardship will disappear when they shall consider, that by how much the greater is the present Payment, by so much the less is the Annual Payment; and that in the whole this publik Insurance is not only upon better Security, but is cheaper and easier to the Insurer, as being Annually, and not at once pay'd.</p>
            <p>That it's no more than turning private into publick Insurance, and making that a publick Benefit which was before sunk into private Interest, and by way of Retaliation for the present Ease of Land, the Land is ready in Aid of Houses, in case of great Conflagrations, which the Fund cannot answer. The Hardship will quite vanish when the Owner shall consider, that the Land Tax (unless very great indeed) will not excuse them from paying as much as is hereby proposed upon some other Tax; and then the Question will be, whether it were not better to pay it upon this, where there is a certain Prospect of a future Recompence, in case of Fire, than to pay half the Sum upon any other account whatsoever, where there can be no Hope or Probability of any Return, upon any account whatsoever.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="half_title">
            <pb facs="tcp:189477:2"/>
            <p>Answers to the Objections Against A General Insurance.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>